[
	{
    	"id": "667",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Which database is a fully managed, petabyte scale data warehouse service in the cloud?",
      	"answers": [
        	"RedShift",
        	"Aurora",
        	"Cassandra",
        	"DynamoDB"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["RedShift"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "668",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      	"question": "When you start out using RedShift you can take advantage of which?",
      	"answers": [
        	"No commitments",
        	"No up-front costs",
        	"A variable rate per GB",
        	"A fixed rate per GB"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["No commitments", "No up-front costs"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "669",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "With RedShift, customers can scale up to _________ or more for $1,000 per ___________?",
      	"answers": [
        	"a petabyte, terabyte per year",
        	"a terabyte, megabyte per year",
        	"a terabyte, terabyte per year",
        	"a petabyte, gigabyte per year"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["a petabyte, terabyte per year"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "670",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      	"question": "With RedShift, you can configure your database as which two options?",
      	"answers": [
        	"multi-node",
        	"single node",
        	"multi-terabyte",
        	"multi-region",
        	"multi-AZ"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["multi-node", "single node"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "671",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      	"question": "With RedShift, when you operate in the multi-node configuration, what are the two types of node you'll have?",
      	"answers": [
        	"leader node",
        	"compute node",
        	"slave node",
        	"passive node",
        	"analytics node"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["leader node", "compute node"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "672",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "With RedShift, the leader node does which?",
      	"answers": [
        	"manages client connections and receives queries",
        	"stores data and performs queries and computations"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["manages client connections and receives queries"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "673",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "With RedShift, the compute node does which?",
      	"answers": [
        	"manages client connections and receives queries",
        	"stores data and performs queries and computations"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["stores data and performs queries and computations"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "674",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "With RedShift, when using multi-node, the configuration can have up to _______ compute nodes?",
      	"answers": [
        	"32",
        	"128",
        	"256",
        	"512"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["128"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "675",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Instead of storing data as a series of rows, RedShift organizes the data by _________?",
      	"answers": [
        	"columns",
        	"documents",
        	"fields",
        	"tables"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["columns"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "676",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Row-based database systems are ideal for ___________?",
      	"answers": [
        	"transaction processing",
        	"data warehousing and analytics",
        	"social network applications",
        	"gaming applications"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["transaction processing"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "677",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Column-based database systems are ideal for ___________?",
      	"answers": [
        	"transaction processing",
        	"data warehousing and analytics",
        	"social network applications",
        	"gaming applications"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["data warehousing and analytics"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "678",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Which type of database systems are ideal for queries that involve aggregates performed over large data sets?",
      	"answers": [
        	"column-based databases",
        	"row-based databases"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["column-based databases"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "679",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Why do column-based databases require far fewer I/Os than row-based databases?",
      	"answers": [
        	"columnar data is stored sequentially over the storage media, thereby greatly improving the query performance",
        	"columnar data takes up less space on the underlying storage media",
        	"columnar data is indexed in a more efficient way than row based data",
        	"row based data is usually stored on magnetic storage, while colmnar data is usually stored on SSD"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["columnar data is stored sequentially over the storage media, thereby greatly improving the query performance"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "680",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Why can columnar data stores be compressed much more than row-based data stores?",
      	"answers": [
        	"because similar data is stored sequentially on disk for column-based data",
        	"because row-based data indexing is less efficient than column- based data indexing",
        	"because row-based data is typically built upon older technology",
        	"row based data is usually stored on magnetic storage, while colmnar data is usually stored on SSD"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["because similar data is stored sequentially on disk for column-based data"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "681",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "RedShift employs __________ and achieves significant compression compared to traditional data stores?",
      	"answers": [
        	"multiple compression techniques",
        	"multiple indexing techniques",
        	"multi-AZ",
        	"direct compression"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["multiple compression techniques"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "682",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "RedShift doesn't require _________ or __________ and therefore uses less space?",
      	"answers": [
        	"indexes, materialized views",
        	"indexes, stored procedures",
        	"stored procedures, materialized views",
        	"indexes, shadow tables"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["indexes, materialized views"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "683",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "When loading your data into empty tables, RedShift samples your data and selects the most appropriate _________?",
      	"answers": [
        	"indexes",
        	"stored procedures",
        	"materialized views",
        	"compression scheme"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["compression scheme"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "684",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "RedShift does Massively Parallel Processing by automatically distributing data and query load across __________?",
      	"answers": [
        	"all nodes",
        	"the appropriate nodes",
        	"the leader node",
        	"all tables"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["all nodes"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "685",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 3",
      	"question": "RedShift is priced via which?",
      	"answers": [
        	"compute node hours",
        	"backup charges",
        	"data transfer charges",
        	"leader node hours"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["compute node hours", "backup charges", "data transfer charges"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "686",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "With RedShift pricing, you are charged for which?",
      	"answers": [
        	"compute nodes",
        	"leader node"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["compute nodes"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "687",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "With RedShift pricing, you are charged for data transfer charges where?",
      	"answers": [
        	"inside your VPC",
        	"outside your VPC"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["inside your VPC"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "688",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "RedShift is encrypted in transit via ________?",
      	"answers": [
        	"SSL",
        	"AES-256"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["SSL"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "688",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "RedShift is encrypted at rest via ________?",
      	"answers": [
        	"SSL",
        	"AES-256"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["AES-256"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "689",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "By default, RedShift takes care of key management?",
      	"answers": [
        	"true",
        	"false"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["true"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "690",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      	"question": "With RedShift you can manage your own keys via which?",
      	"answers": [
        	"HSM",
        	"AWS Key Management Service",
        	"Customer provided Key Management",
        	"Kerberos Key Management"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["HSM", "AWS Key Management Service"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "691",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Which types of workloads does Elasticache not help with?",
      	"answers": [
        	"Media Sharing",
        	"Social Networks",
        	"Gaming",
        	"Q&A Portals",
        	"Bitcoin Mining"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["Bitcoin Mining"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "692",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Elasticache can significantly improve latency and throughput for which type of workload?",
      	"answers": [
        	"Read-heavy",
        	"Write-heavy"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["Read-heavy"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "693",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      	"question": "With Elasticache, cached information can include which?",
      	"answers": [
        	"results of I/O intensive DB queries",
        	"results of computationally-intensive calculations",
        	"results of I/O intensive DB writes",
        	"results of distributed application data retrievals"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["results of I/O intensive DB queries", "results of computationally-intensive calculations"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "694",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 2",
      	"question": "What are the two types of caching engines supported by Elasticache?",
      	"answers": [
        	"Memcached",
        	"Redis",
        	"Cassandra",
        	"Hadoop"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["Memcached", "Redis"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "695",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Which of the types of caching engines supported by Elasticache is an open source in-memory key/value store?",
      	"answers": [
        	"Memcached",
        	"Redis",
        	"Cassandra",
        	"Hadoop"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["Redis"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "696",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Which of the types of caching engines supported by Elasticache supprts master/slave replication and multi-AZ which can be used to achieve cross-AZ redundancy?",
      	"answers": [
        	"Memcached",
        	"Redis",
        	"Cassandra",
        	"Hadoop"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["Redis"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "697",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Which type of database service is best if your database is particularly read-heavy nd not prone to frequent changes?",
      	"answers": [
        	"Elasticache",
        	"RedShift",
        	"RDS"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["Elasticache"]
    	}
  	},
  	{
    	"id": "698",
    	"category": "Cloud Concepts",
    	"info": {
      	"subcategory": "Databases",
      	"questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      	"question": "Which type of database service is best if management keeps running OLAP transactions against it, making the database performance stressed?",
      	"answers": [
        	"Elasticache",
        	"RedShift",
        	"RDS"
      	],
      	"correctAnswer": ["RedShift"]
    	}
  	}
]

